<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
To change this license header, choose License Headers in Project Properties.
To change this template file, choose Tools | Templates
and open the template in the editor.
-->


<randomcard>
    <item>
        <card_id>1</card_id>
        <card_name>The Dragon</card_name>
        <card_description>
            Roll the die to determine which area on the board will be hit
            by the dragon. Remove all minions (including demons and
            trolls), any trouble marker, and any building from the area
            affected.   
        </card_description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <card_id>2</card_id>
        <card_name>Flood</card_name>
        <card_description>
            Roll the die twice to see which areas are affected by flood.
            Areas rolled that are adjacent to the river are affected by flood.
            In player order, starting with the active player, each player
            must move their minions from the affected areas to adjacent
            areas. You cannot move your minion to another area affected
            by flood. You can still move to an area adjacent to the river.
            Buildings, trolls, and demons remain in the areas and are not
            affected by flooding
        </card_description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <card_id>3</card_id>
        <card_name>Fire</card_name>
        <card_description>
            Roll the die to establish the area of the fire. If there is no
            building in the rolled area then the random event ends
            without effect. If there is a building in the area then remove it
            from the board and roll the die again. If the next area rolled is
            adjacent to the previous area and there is a building in it then
            remove that building too (the fire has spread). You continue
            rolling in this manner until you roll an area that either does
            not contain a building or that is not adjacent to the last area
            you rolled.
        </card_description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <card_id>4</card_id>
        <card_name>Fog</card_name>
        <card_description>
            Draw and discard the top five cards from the draw pile. Make
            sure you and the rest of the players can see which cards have
            been discarded
        </card_description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <card_id>5</card_id>
        <card_name>Riots</card_name>
        <card_description>
            If there are eight or more trouble markers on the board then
            the game ends immediately. You now work out who has won
            by adding up points (see page 6). Please note that if a player
            is Commander Vimes then they do not win at this stage,
            although they may still win on points.
        </card_description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <card_id>6</card_id>
        <card_name>Explosion</card_name>
        <card_description>
            Roll the die and remove any building in the area of the
            same number
        </card_description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <card_id>7</card_id>
        <card_name>Mysterious Murders!</card_name>
        <card_description>
            You roll one die and remove a minion of your choice from the
            area of the same number. You then pass the die to the player
            to your left, who rolls it and removes a minion of their choice
            from the area of the same number. Repeat this procedure until
            all players have rolled the die once. If you roll an area and only
            you have minions there then you must remove one of them
        </card_description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <card_id>8</card_id>
        <card_name>Demons from the Dungeon Dimensions </card_name>
        <card_description>
            Roll the die four times and place one demon minion piece in
            each of the areas matching the numbers rolled. More than one
            demon can end up in an area. If there is not a trouble marker
            in the area that a demon is placed in then place such a marker,
            even if there is no other minion in the area. While there are
            one or more demons in an area the power on the City Area
            card cannot be used and any building there has a value of zero.
            The area also cannot be controlled by any player nor does it
            count as an occupied area for Vetinari. If an area still has one
            or more demons in it at the end of the game then nobody
            scores any points for minions or buildings there. Demons
            can be moved or removed from the board in the same way
            as minions.
        </card_description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <card_id>9</card_id>
        <card_name>Subsidence</card_name>
        <card_description>
            All players must pay $2 for each building they have on the
            board. If they cannot pay for a building then it is removed
            from the board
        </card_description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <card_id>10</card_id>
        <card_name>Bloody Stupid Johnson</card_name>
        <card_description>
            Roll the die. If the City Area Card of the same number is
            in play then it is set to one side and is no longer in the game,
            i.e. the power on the card is not in effect. Also, the owner
            of the card must remove one minion from the same area as
            the card. The building still counts towards control of the
            area and retains its monetary value at the end of the game
        </card_description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <card_id>11</card_id>
        <card_name>Trolls</card_name>
        <card_description>
            Roll the die three times and place one troll piece in each
            area of the same number. More than one troll can end up
            in an area. Remember to place a trouble marker if there
            is already one or more minions in the area. Trolls are like
            minions, except they do not belong to any player. They affect
            your ability to control an area, in that you must treat them as
            belonging to ‘another player’. You can move or remove them
            from the board in the same way as a minion.
        </card_description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <card_id>12</card_id>
        <card_name>Earthquake</card_name>
        <card_description>
            Roll the die twice and remove any buildings from the areas
            of the same number, if any
        </card_description>
    </item>
</randomcard>