<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
To change this license header, choose License Headers in Project Properties.
To change this template file, choose Tools | Templates
and open the template in the editor.
-->


<secretcard>
        <item>
                <card_id>1</card_id>
                <card_name>Lord Vetinari</card_name>
                <card_description>
                    you win if at the
                    beginning of your turn you have a certain
                    number of minions in different areas on
                    the board (think of them as your spies).
                    With two players you need to have
                    minions in at least eleven different areas.
                    With three players you need to have
                    minions in at least ten different areas.
                    With four players you need to have
                    minions in at least nine different areas.
                    Areas must be free of demons
                </card_description>
        </item>
        <item>
                <card_id>2</card_id>
                <card_name>Lord Selachii</card_name>
                <card_description>
                    you win if at
                    the beginning of your turn you control a certain number of
                    areas. If there are only two of you playing then you need to
                    control seven areas, if there are three of you then you need to
                    control five areas, and if there are four of you then you need
                    to control four areas. You control an area if you have more
                    playing pieces in it than any single other player (a playing
                    piece being a minion or a building). You would also have to
                    have more pieces there than the total number of trolls in the
                    area. You cannot control an area that contains one or more
                    demons. The presence of a trouble marker does not affect
                    the control of an area.
                </card_description>
        </item>
        <item>
                <card_id>3</card_id>
                <card_name>Lord Rust</card_name>
                <card_description>
                    you win if at
                    the beginning of your turn you control a certain number of
                    areas. If there are only two of you playing then you need to
                    control seven areas, if there are three of you then you need to
                    control five areas, and if there are four of you then you need
                    to control four areas. You control an area if you have more
                    playing pieces in it than any single other player (a playing
                    piece being a minion or a building). You would also have to
                    have more pieces there than the total number of trolls in the
                    area. You cannot control an area that contains one or more
                    demons. The presence of a trouble marker does not affect
                    the control of an area.
                </card_description>
        </item>
        <item>
                <card_id>4</card_id>
                <card_name> Lord de Worde</card_name>
                <card_description>
                    you win if at
                    the beginning of your turn you control a certain number of
                    areas. If there are only two of you playing then you need to
                    control seven areas, if there are three of you then you need to
                    control five areas, and if there are four of you then you need
                    to control four areas. You control an area if you have more
                    playing pieces in it than any single other player (a playing
                    piece being a minion or a building). You would also have to
                    have more pieces there than the total number of trolls in the
                    area. You cannot control an area that contains one or more
                    demons. The presence of a trouble marker does not affect
                    the control of an area.
                </card_description>
        </item>
        <item>
                <card_id>5</card_id>
                <card_name>Dragon King of Arms</card_name>
                <card_description>
                    If at the beginning of your turn
                    there are eight trouble markers on the board then you win.
                    The rationale is that the city has fallen into more chaos than
                    normal and people want the king back (who would be
                    controlled by you).
                </card_description>
        </item>
        <item>
                <card_id>6</card_id>
                <card_name>Chrysoprase</card_name>
                <card_description>
                    If at the beginning of your turn your net worth
                    (your cash plus the monetary cost of each building you have)
                    is $50 or more then you win the game. Please note that any
                    loans you have taken out count as $12 against your total
                    worth (certain cards allow you to take out loans).
                </card_description>
        </item>
        <item>
                <card_id>7</card_id>
                <card_name>Commander Vimes</card_name>
                <card_description>
                    you win if nobody else wins by the
                    time the draw pile has been exhausted.
                    If the game ends due to the draw pile running out AND
                    nobody has the Commander Vimes Personality card, then
                    the winner is the player with the most points. Each minion
                    on the board is worth five points. Each building is worth a
                    number of points equal to its monetary cost. Each $1 in hand
                    is worth one point. If you have the Dent card or the Bank card
                    then you must pay back the amount noted on the card. If you
                    cannot do so then you lose fifteen points each. In the case of a
                    tie the tied player with the highest monetary value City Area
                    card is the winner. If there is still a tie then the tied players
                    shared the honours of a joint win.
                </card_description>
        </item>
</secretcard>

